<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utopian Io on Open R</title>
    <link>/zh/tags/utopian-io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Utopian Io on Open R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 16:34:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/zh/tags/utopian-io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>bookdownplus gallery: a web app for displaying and sharing bookdown templates</title>
      <link>/zh/blog/2018/09/23/2018-09-23-bookdownplus-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 16:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/blog/2018/09/23/2018-09-23-bookdownplus-gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I collected some LaTeX templates when learning LaTeX. However, my interest in LaTeX was gone after submitting my PhD dissertation. I should have deleted these templates if they had not been so small. They would never be useful in the future, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I started writing the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://xuer.pzhao.org&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;Learning R: R for Rookies&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;. Unexpectedly, MS Word could not satisfy me with the typesetting. You know what I mean if you have experience (and pain) in writing a long book or dissertation with Word. Actually I suffered more, but I do not want to talk about it. I was sure that LaTeX could, but I would rather not use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a bolt out of the blue, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=bookdown&#34;&gt;bookdown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[New Project] advr: an R package for the scientific research on trace gas advection flux density</title>
      <link>/zh/blog/2018/06/14/2018-06-14-advr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 13:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/blog/2018/06/14/2018-06-14-advr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Carbon dioxide (CO~2~) is one of the key green house gases which play an important role in the global climate change. In academia, the sources and sinks of CO~2~ are estimated with the flux density, e.g. the amount of CO~2~ passing through a unit area in a unit time. Estimates of net ecosystem CO~2~ exchange have been attracting a lot of attention. The research on the advection flux takes care of the contribution of the advection term to the CO~2~ balance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a mirror/backup site for your own steem posts in 30 minutes - 30 分钟搭建自己的 steem 镜像备份网站</title>
      <link>/zh/blog/2017/11/06/2017-11-06-build-a-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 09:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/blog/2017/11/06/2017-11-06-build-a-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I built two mirror sites for my steem posts (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dapeng.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;mirror 1&lt;/a&gt;，&lt;a href=&#34;https://steemit.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;mirror 2&lt;/a&gt;) as backups, which are synced automatically everyday, thanks to steemsql and steemdata. The mirror sites are very useful:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>